Luke Belliveau

Software Engineer

linkedin.com/in/lukebelliveau github.com/lukebelliveau hi@lukebelliveau.dev 603-320-9505 Luke is a software delivery consultant with 7 years of experience engineering full stack web applications and services at enterprise scale. If you need to get an application built or some code untangled, there's a good chance he can help you out.

Work Experience

Technical Partner ZUUT Oct 2021 - Current

Luke collaborated with ZUUT's founder, working from the product's inception to turn his ideas into reality. Handling all facets of development, he:

- Built a full-fledged interactive computer aided design web application, enabling users to save, share and collaborate in real time on gardening plots featuring a deep interaction & collision detection engine
- Designed and implemented an account and data management system using Firebase services such as Authentication, Realtime DB, and Cloud Storage
- Implemented system & interface for users to compare, contrast, and purchase equipment for their grow designs featuring an affiliate link system using Amazon's APIs, successfully qualifying ZUUT for Amazon's Associates Program
- Integrated content management systems enabling nontechnical users to update item metadata and create blog content with a simple interface, using Airtable and Contentful
- · Hired & managed a team of freelance developers & designers to accelerate development

Software Delivery Consultant NuWave Technologies

Feb 2021 - Current

Luke managed the development and maintenance of NuWave's suite of web applications. As a software delivery consultant, he:

- Managed development of the Prizm API Gateway management console from inception to post-launch
- Engineered a successful migration from AngularJS to React for all of the company's web applications
- Created new automated testing pipelines and ran workshops and training, facilitated a culture of testing and continuous integration
- Played an instrumental role in the interview, evaluation & mentorship of new hires

Senior Cloud Infra Engineer Grubhub

Oct 2018 - Feb 2020

On Grubhub's Cloud Infrastructure team, Luke designed & implemented frameworks, tools, and services that enabled web, mobile, and site reliability engineers to do their jobs as efficiently as they can. In his time at GrubHub, he:

- Engineered changes to core framework to facilitate communication between microservices in a new Envoy service mesh architecture
- Led integration of SMS service with a new provider, handling the development, evaluation, and communication with stakeholders on both ends
- Ownership of Notifications stack of microservices in Java (with Guice and Spring), spanning SMS, mobile push, email, and fax functionalities
- Built a service in React & Python used by Site Reliability Engineers to view system status and make changes during outages
- Designed the architecture & database schemas for a new notifications platform. This service was used by product and marketing teams at GrubHub to manage notifications for email, SMS, push, and fax.

Senior Software Engineer

Bachelors Computer Science

Thoughtworks

May 2018 - Oct 2018

2011 - 2016

As an Associate and later Senior Engineer at ThoughtWorks, Luke worked on software delivery teams in a variety of domains such as health insurance administration, e-commerce, and cybersecurity. Among his responsibilities and achievements:

- · Built a cybersecurity admin panel with rich interactions and data visualizations, built with Vue & Highcharts
- Facilitated front-end training sessions for the company, coordinating speakers and workshops for bimonthly meetups in a global community of React and Vue developers
- Designed APIs and data pipelines to facilitate a seamless integration of Kroger's e-commerce platform with a newly acquired subsidiary
- Worked with designers and executive stakeholders to determine key features/specifications and break them into manageable tasks
- Worked on a backend-for-frontend in Golang to aggregate, analyze and perform operations on a large breadth of logs before serving them to the client

Languages	TypeScript, JavaScript, Java, Python, Golang, C#
Deploy, Automation, Hosting	AWS, Digital Ocean, Firebase, Jenkins, Spinnaker, GitHub Actions, Vercel
Frameworks & Build Tooling	React, Next.js, Redux, Vite, Konva, Highcharts
Testing	Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Vitest, Cypress, Jest, JUnit, Chai / Mocha, Selenium, Ginkgo
Education ————	

University of Connecticut